# **Rachel Esteve**

Senior Professional Administration Officer rachiraesteve@yahoo.com | London, UK

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a conscientious, committed individual who sets high personal standards, adaptable and at ease working in a flexible and changing environment. I have several years of experience working in the High Education sector as a Senior Administrator Officer with extended experience and have great leadership skills. I enjoyed being part of a close team, working together to achieve results, and have also spent time working alone, motivated to organise and prioritise workload to meet deadlines. A fast learner with great computer skills, and experience in Microsoft packages. I am currently looking for the opportunity to put these skills to full use in a new and challenging role.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Intermediate Excel

Microsoft Office

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Assessments Officer (Exams, Assessments and Timetabling) | King's College, London May 2023 – August 2023

- Coordinated the preparation of scheduling, and publishing of draft and final examinations timetables for the annual assessment periods.
- Managed personalised Access Arrangement applications made by students, incorporating their needs into examinations timetables and coordination activities.
- Organising and planning large-scale events and examinations both on campus and in large external venues.
- Organising, assisting, and training Invigilation staff, under the guidance of the Examinations Manager and the Head of Examinations.
- Provided a comprehensive enquiry service for members of academic staff, administrative staff, and students, on all matters concerning the examinations processes.
- Collaborating with colleagues in faculties and other central teams to maintain accurate, up to date Assessment records using our Student Records Management System (SITS)
- Importing of Student Assessment data, I.e., both coursework and examination marks
- Managing the production and issue of all official university certificates and transcripts
- Managing the authentication of degree certificates and transcripts

# Faculty Senior Co-Ordinator (Quality Assurance and Enhancement) | Kingston University, London May 2022 – April 2023

- Coordinated the Annual Review, which includes but is not limited to Programme Specifications, Module Descriptors and Indicative Summative Assessment Maps.
- Maintained the central record of Professional, Statutory & Regulatory Body (PSRB) accreditations.
- Coordinated and managed the appointment of External Examiners and provided appropriate support to course teams and Assistant Registrars.
- Supported the process of Continual Enhancement of the University's Quality Assurance and Enhancement processes and provided advice and guidance on those processes.
- Managed the operation of the Collaborative Joint Executive Committees, by taking the role of Clerk to the Committees.
- Managed the University's Collaborative Partnership contract reviews and updates.
- Monitored and supported the completion of Annual Monitoring and Enhancement forms and processes.
- Undertook research activities about Quality Assurance and Enhancement.
- Reviewing documentation submitted for the re/validation of programmes to ensure alignment with Academic Regulations and the Academic Standards and Quality framework.
- Secretary to validation/re-validation events including writing reports, liaising with the panel and programme team, and reviewing the response to conditions and recommendations set by the panel.
- Executive Secretary to the Faculty Education Sub-committee, School Education Committee Sub-committee, Course and Module Modification Panel including the writing and preparation of reports, papers, agendas, and minutes and ensuring the implementation of actions arising from the meetings.

### Registry Administrator (Assessments and Quality) | Coventry University, London

June 2021 -Apr 2022

- Led and managed extensions and deferrals for Extenuating Circumstances cases. Considering cases through the examination of statements and supporting evidence and approving or rejecting requests per university regulations.
- Secretary to the Deferral Panel, producing annual reports on deferrals and extensions and providing training on the process.
- Supporting role in the academic appeals process. Assisting the Academic Appeals Secretary by processing and investigating case details on behalf of the Assessment Review Group.

- Secretary to Assessment Boards, Boards of Study, Faculty Review and Approval Panel, Academic Misconduct Meetings, Disciplinary Hearings, and other Committees.
- A trained Student Conciliator, assisting in matters of conciliation and complaints, promoting good practice throughout the institution, and providing administrative support for related processes. Assisting with complaints, appeals, academic misconduct, and disciplinary processes relating to students.
- Processing all student records and module options, ensuring accurate student data records are maintained.
- Led all matters relating to External Examiners i.e., being the first point of contact, processing claims submitted by External Examiners and following up on module moderations.
- Organisation and management of Programme Assessment Boards (Exam boards).
- Overseeing Student Lifecycle processes around assessment across the academic year
- Maintaining accurate, up to date Assessment records using Coventry's Student Records Management System
- Importing of Student Assessment data i.e., both coursework and examination marks
- Providing guidance on the university's processes, procedures and the regulations, and training colleagues in their use

# ASK4HELP & Student Progress Administrator/Co-Ordinator | Northumbria University, London

June 2018 - May 2021

- Managed all ASK4HELP processes (ASK4HELP is the University's single point of contact for all students that enables them to access professional advice, guidance, and support).
- Deputised as the ASK4HELP Manager in the interim of getting a new Manager during Covid-19. Direct line management of 5 people.
- Supported progression and Awards Boards including preparation; marks entry and communicating student awards and progressions.
- Led academic misconduct meetings; Supported student staff programme committees; assessment monitoring including invigilation, arranged exam paperwork and exam pack support, communicated and processed Change of Circumstances requests; included a pause in study, withdrawals, and course transfers; supporting student enrolment.
- Experience in using SITS and Blackboard to handle and monitor students' records. Managed complex student welfare issues such as unplanned pregnancy, mental health issues and homelessness.
- Worked closely with admissions, recruitment, and academics team to ensure smooth running and planning of enrolment. Assisted with reporting enrolment data through MOSA and SQL reporting. Handling attendance recording/monitoring via SAMS (in house attendance monitoring system).
- Reviewing Stage 1 student appeals and complaints and coordinating Stage 2 complaints/panels.
- Organisation and management of student enrolment and Welcome Weeks for 3 intakes per year.

# Learning Co-Ordinator | Somerset House, London

Jan 2016 -May 2018

- Delivered activities and sessions as directed by the Assistant Curators of Learning and/or the Learning Manager, ensuring a full knowledge and understanding of the subject material as per the session notes and training.
- Completed administrative activities relevant to the role.
- Managed the timing of sessions to ensure completion within the allocated timescale and explained activities and educational content in terms appropriate to the audience.
- Supervised the use of premises and equipment being used during sessions in line with Health & Safety Policy and practice.
- Monitored handling of objects and resources for wear and tear; supervised groups when using the galleries and exhibition spaces. Making sure that routine evaluation of the learning Programme, through formal and informal methodologies, is done and training other Casual Learning Facilitators to deliver formal Learning Sessions.
- Acted as a point of contact for School groups to keep them informed on the latest programmes, sessions and events and promote these as appropriate. Demonstrated commitment to Equality and Diversity and an understanding of how this commitment applies to the role of a Learning Facilitator.
- Managed and oversaw the process of hiring and managing temporary staff.

#### **EDUCATION**

• PgCert in Higher Education Administration, Management and Leadership Management | NTU

Oct 2022 - Oct 2023

• Level 3 BTEC Extended Diploma | North-West Kent College

Sept 2012 - Jul 2014

• AS Level | Welling School Sixth Form

Sept 2011 - Jul 2012

• GCSE | Welling School

Sept 2006 - Jul 2010

### **Professional Body Membership**

• AUA Oct 2022 – Present

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.